<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Rdata Luxembourg</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Rdata Luxembourg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping unemployment in Luxembourg</title>
      <link>/portfolio/2017-07-11-unemp_lux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/2017-07-11-unemp_lux/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I show various ways to create maps using R. You’ll need to install a lot of packages and download two data sets; the unemployment rate in Luxembourg as well as a shapefile.
To get the unemployment rate in Luxembourg, you can take a look at our previous blog post and simply run the following lines:
library(rvest) library(dplyr) library(purrr) library(janitor) library(tidyr) page_unemp &amp;lt;- read_html(&amp;quot;http://www.statistiques.public.lu/stat/TableViewer/tableViewHTML.aspx?ReportId=12950&amp;amp;IF_Language=eng&amp;amp;MainTheme=2&amp;amp;FldrName=3&amp;amp;RFPath=91&amp;quot;) data_raw &amp;lt;- page_unemp %&amp;gt;% html_nodes(&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping data from STATEC&#39;s public tables</title>
      <link>/portfolio/2017-04-21-scraping-data-from-statec-s-public-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 06:34:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/2017-04-21-scraping-data-from-statec-s-public-tables/</guid>
      <description>A lot of open data is available in Luxembourg’s open data portal, but sometimes, it is not very easy to download. In the video below, I give you an example of such data and show how you can use rvest to get the data easily.
After watching the video, take a look at the code below. This code does two things; first it scrapes the data, and then it puts the data in a tidy format fur further processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Rdata Luxembourg!</title>
      <link>/portfolio/2017-04-21-welcome-to-rdata-luxembourg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/2017-04-21-welcome-to-rdata-luxembourg/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Rdata Luxembourg! This blog is dedicated to Luxembourg&amp;rsquo;s users of the R programming language. In this blog we will publish tips, tricks and tutorials about the R programming language and present applications using (but not only) open data from Luxembourg.
We are a small group of dedicated users of the R programming language, all living or working in Luxembourg. You can get to know us better by clicking here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>