<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rdata Luxembourg</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rdata Luxembourg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R d3js, and how to make them communicate</title>
      <link>/portfolio/2017-05-16-d3jsandr_communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/2017-05-16-d3jsandr_communication/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone,
In this post we will focus on how to send a message from R to javascript. More precisely, we will focus on the basic keywords and knowledge to integrate a d3.js graph into shiny, just like here. If you have any issue to make shiny and javascript communicate after reading this post, I suggest you to go back to this simple shiny app from Rstudio.
First of all, create a folder where you will put your data file (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping data from STATEC&#39;s public tables</title>
      <link>/portfolio/2017-04-21-scraping-data-from-statec-s-public-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 06:34:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/2017-04-21-scraping-data-from-statec-s-public-tables/</guid>
      <description>A lot of open data is available in Luxembourg’s open data portal, but sometimes, it is not very easy to download. In the video below, I give you an example of such data and show how you can use rvest to get the data easily.
After watching the video, take a look at the code below. This code does two things; first it scrapes the data, and then it puts the data in a tidy format fur further processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Rdata Luxembourg!</title>
      <link>/portfolio/2017-04-21-welcome-to-rdata-luxembourg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/2017-04-21-welcome-to-rdata-luxembourg/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Rdata Luxembourg! This blog is dedicated to Luxembourg&amp;rsquo;s users of the R programming language. In this blog we will publish tips, tricks and tutorials about the R programming language and present applications using (but not only) open data from Luxembourg.
We are a small group of dedicated users of the R programming language, all living or working in Luxembourg. You can get to know us better by clicking here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in touch</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Want to get in touch with us? Send us an email: contact at rdata dot lu. You can also follow our twitter accounts @rdata_lu, @Mista_Woza and @brodriguesco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who are we?</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Bruno Rodrigues Research assistant at STATEC interested in econometrics, machine learning and numerical methods in general.
I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of the R programming language and its awesome community. My way of giving back to this awesome community is to share my knowledge!
I also have another blog, which is more focused on econometrics with R and general R programming tips over here.
Kevin Rosamont Data scientist interested in Data analysis and Visualisation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>